Andrew Ellicott Douglass papers, 1867-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Tree-Ring Materials, 1894-1966
  - Correspondence (general). January 1925-June 1930 (Box 65)
  - Correspondence (general). July 1930-June 1933 (Box 66)
  - Correspondence (general). July 1933-December 1935 (Box 67)
  - Correspondence (general). January 1936-May 1938 (Box 68)
  - Correspondence (general). June 1938-December 1942 (Box 69)
  - Correspondence (general). 1943-1948 (Box 70)
  - Correspondence (general). 1949-1960 (Box 71)
  - Correspondence: Ernst Antevs. 1917, 1925-1935 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Wiliam H. Beveridge. 1922 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: L.F. Brady. 1921-1937, 1950 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Hebert J. Brown. 1929-1933 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: reprints from H.J. Brown, I. (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: reprints from H.J. Brown, II. (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: reprints from H.J. Brown, III. (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: "Long Range Weather Forecast Service," by H.J. Brown. (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Harold S. Colton. 1928-1956 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: F.C. Craighead. 1922, 1930-1932 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: H. Faurest Davis. 1931-1947 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Charles G. Dawes. 1938-1940 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Gerard DeGeer & Ebba H. DeGeer. 1920-1954, 1959 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: G.H. Ellis (Montana Curves). 1931 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: J.W. Fewkes. 1917, 1922 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Foundation for the study of cycles. 1940-1943, 1950, 1952 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: L. Giddings & University of Alaska. 1936-1942 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: L. Giddings & University of Alaska. 1943-1956 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Halpert P. Gillette. 1928-1955 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Harold S. Gladwin. 1926-1948, 1957 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Madison Grant. 1924, 1928, 1933-1937 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Waldo S. Glock. 1930-1947, 1958 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: W.S. Glock, "Principles and Methods of Tree-Ring Analysis." Carnegie Institution of Washington. 1937 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: W.S. Glock (articles and talks). (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Lyndon L. Hargrave. 1928-1948 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Emil W. Haury. 1929-1946, 1956 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Florence Hawley. 1933-1949 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Edgar L. Hewett. 1920-1929 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Frederick W. Hodge. 1922, 1930, 1936, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Ellsworth Huntington. 1911-1949 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Inigio Jones. 1930-1950 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: A.V. Kidder. 1922-1934, 1957 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: A.L. Kroeber. 1922, 1928, 1930-1931 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: T.O. McGrath (sunspot theory). 1931-1933 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: John C. McGregor. 1931-1948 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Meriden Gravure Co. 1939-1942 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Earl H. Morris. 1919-1932 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Earl H. Morris. 1933-1950 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Jesse L. Nusbaum. 1922-1923, 1929-1950 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: G.A. Pearson. 1914, 1918-1937 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: T.A. Riordan & M.J. Riordan. 1902-1944 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Russian. 1923-1938 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Scripps Institution of Oceanography. 1931-1938 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: W.S. Stallings, Jr. 1931-1950 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: A. Streiff. 1923-1937 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: R.H. Wheeler. 1936-1938, 1951 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Tree Ring Bulletin. 1934-1953 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Clarence G. White. 1919-1938 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Clark Wissler. 1914-1941 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Gilbert H. Grosvenor. 1915-1946 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Neil M. Judd. 1921-1959 (Box 77, Folder 2-5)
  - Articles by Neil M. Judd. (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): First application to Carnegie Institution. 1906 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): Ralph W. Chaney. 1926, 1929-1936 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): D.T. MacDougal. 1899, 1916-1940 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): John C. Merriam. 1921-1930 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): John C. Merriam. 1931-1934 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): John C. Merriam. 1935-1936 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): John C. Merriam. 1937-1943 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): Appraisal of Carnegie Equipment & Tree Ring Collections. 1931 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): A.E.D. notes and thoughts on the Carnegie Institution. 1935-1936 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): Desert Laboratory, Tucson, AZ. (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): general. 1920-1931 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): general. 1932 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): general. 1933-1939, 1945, 1958 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): annual report. 1920-1934 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): annual report. 1934-1938 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): Vannevar Bush. 1938-1944, 1951, 1954, 1956 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): Frederic C. Clements. 1914-1949 (Box 80, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): W.A. Pestell. 1929-1940 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Carnegie Institution): H.A. Spoehr. 1928-1940 (Box 80, Folder 4-7)
  - Carnegie Institution: Accounts. 1918-1931 (Box 81)
  - Carnegie Institutions: Accounts. 1932-1935 (Box 82)
  - Carnegie Institution: Accounts. 1936-1937 (Box 83, Folder 1-4)
  - Carnegie Institution: Bank statements and correspondence. (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Institution: Equipment inventory. (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Gifts and Grants: Tree Ring Aid by source. 1933 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Gifts and Grants: National Geographic Society Fund Accounts. 1923-1928 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Gifts and Grants: National Geographic Society Fund Accounts. December 1928-June 1930 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Gifts and Grants: National Geographic Society Fund Accounts. 1933-1935 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Gifts and Grants: National Geographic Society Fund, bank statements. 1924-1930 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Gifts and Grants: Elizabeth Thompson Science Fund Accounts. 1914-1917 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Gifts and Grants: White Research Fund Accounts. 1919 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Gifts and Grants: American Museum of Natural History Accounts. 1919-1920 (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Gifts and Grants: Douglass Research Fund Accounts. 1935-1938 (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Gifts and Grants: Office of Naval Research Contract (Tree Ring Hydrology). 1950-1953 (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Gifts and Grants: Douglass Grant (from J.L. Pratt). 1951-1959 (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Gifts and Grants: Miscellaneous funds, gifts, grants. 1918-1949 (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Tree Ring Accounts: American Association for the Advancement of Science. 1918 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Tree Ring Accounts: Carnegie-Clements. 1918-1935 (Box 85, Folder 2-4)
  - Tree Ring Accounts: Douglass Research Fund. 1935-1939 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Tree Ring Accounts: Elizabeth Thompson Science Fund. 1914-1916 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Tree Ring Accounts: National Geographic Society. 1924-1930 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Tree Ring Accounts: White Research Fund. 1919-1926 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Reseach: University of Arizona Administration (these files include correspondence with University of Arizona officials, plans, administrative and personnel matters, various University communications and announcements, notes about the Laboratory's reorganization of offices and materials, etc. 1936-1951 (Box 86)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: University of Arizona Administration and Annual Reports. 1941-1959 (Box 87)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Requisition Books and Budget and Accounts (these files include notes on proposed budgets, purchase orders, bills, receipts, records of student wages, official ledger sheets from the University of Arizona Business Office, and some corespondence regarding budget changes). RESTRICTED: Permission to use must be obtained in writing from the director of the Laboratory of Tree Ring Research. 1938-1946 (Box 88)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Reseach: Budget and Accounts. RESTRICTED: Permission to use must be obtained in writing from the director of the Laboratory of Tree Ring Research. 1946-1959 (Box 89)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Reseach (Edmund Schulman): Correspondence with A.E. Douglass. RESTRICTED: Permission to use must be obtained in writing from the director of the Laboratory of Tree Ring Research. 1932-1954 (Box 90, Folder 1-3)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Reseach (Edmund Schulman): miscellaneous (personal). RESTRICTED: Permission to use must be obtained in writing from the director of the Laboratory of Tree Ring Research. (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Reseach (Edmund Schulman): A.E.D. "Thoughts about Edmund." RESTRICTED: Permission to use must be obtained in writing from the director of the Laboratory of Tree Ring Research. 1946-1955 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Reseach (Edmund Schulman): "The American Humanity Code," (an unfinished manuscript by A.E.D., inspired in part, by his relationship with Edmund Schulman). RESTRICTED: Permission to use must be obtained in writing from the director of the Laboratory of Tree Ring Research. 1949-1952 (Box 90, Folder 6-7)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence with Pacific Northwest. 1943-1944 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence with Mississippi Valley. 1941-1945 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence with W.S. Stallings. 1939-1958 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence with H. Wexler. 1939-1951 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence with Mexicans. 1942-1946 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence with Scandinavians. 1941-1950 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): military deferment. 1943-1945 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): University of Arizona Accelerated Program of Basic Research in Hydrology. 1951-1952 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): articles and publications. (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): correspondence, "Dendroclimatic Changes in Semiarid America." (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): bibliography work. (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Edmund Schulman): lectures. 1935-1950 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (projects): Manitobea-Saskatchewan-Montana problem of droughts. 1930-1932 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (projects): Colorado River Run-off project (correspondence). 1941-1942 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (projects): Colorado River Run-off project (report, accounts, miscellaneous material). 1941-1942 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (projects): Co-Operative plan with Nebraska. 1938-1939 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (projects): Egyptian project. 1933, 1938-1942 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (projects): South America and E. Shulman's trip. 1937-1954 (Box 92, Folder 6-8)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Tree Ring and Cycle historical material. 1921-1955 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Appeal to Rockefeller Foundation (correspondence). 1937-1946 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Keys (record of). 1921, 1931-1951 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Microfilms. 1938-1941, 1956 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Old films. 1948, 1950-1952 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Photography notes. 1933-1954 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Tree Ring instruments (designed by A.E.D.). (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Tree Ring sites (includes photographs, notes, maps, drawings). (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research: Visitors to the laboratory. 1939-1957 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Astronomy 211, Tree Ring Interpretation. 1929-1930 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Astronomy 211, Tree Ring Interpretation and Astronomy 212, Research. 1930-1933 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Astronomy 211, Tree Ring Interpretation, Astronomy 212, Research, and Edmund Schulman's Master's Degree. 1933-1935 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Anthropology 211, Dendrochronology and Anthropology 212, Research. 1936-1944 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Lectures for "Tree Ring Interpretation." 1930-1936 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Lectures for "Tree Ring Interpretation." 1933 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Miscellaneous lectures to University classes. (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Anthropology 160, Introduction to Dendrochronology. 1941-1942 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Tree Ring Classes: Anthropology 160, Introduction to Dendrochronology. 1942-1943 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Tree Ring Exhibits: Sequoia section, Arizona State Museum (correspondence, photographs, clippings, etc). 1931-1932, 1938 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Tree Ring Exhibits: Panorama for the American Museum of Natural History. 1935 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Tree Ring Exhibits: Panorama for the Arizona State Museum. 1939 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Tree Ring Exhibits: Miscellaneous exhibits. 1948-1949 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Tree Ring Film by A.E.D. 1932-1933 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Tree Ring Film: Tree Ring Story (16mm movie). 1938-1940 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Tree Ring Article: "Trees--Nature's Clock and Weather Stations," by Tamara Andreeva. 1946 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Tree Ring Article: "Tree Rings Tell a Story," by Betty M. Nelson. 1947 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Tree Ring Film: "The Story of Trees" (Television Strip by Tom Bailey). 1949 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Tree Ring Lecture: "The Story of Tree Rings" (Kodachrome slide lecture by W.H. Harlow). 1950 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Geochronology. Edited by Terah L. Smiley. University of Arizona Press. 1955 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Tree Ring clippings. 1911-1966 (Box 96)
  - National Parks (general). (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - National Parks and Monuments (Arizona). (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - National Parks and Monuments (California, Colorado, Utah). (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Sequoia and General Grant National Parks. (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Yellowstone National Park. (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Yosemite National Park. (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Pike's Peak. (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Redwoods (miscellaneous material, photographs). (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Forests and Forestry (miscellaneous material). (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Forests and Forestry (Swedish publications). (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: National Geographic Society Plotting Machine. 1924 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Yellowstone Drill. 1929 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Macbeth Illuminometer. 1930, 1950-1951 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Acuity Meter. 1936-1937 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (Bausch and Lomb). 1929-1950 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (Arthur R. Hanks). 1918-1925 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (Keuffel and Esser). 1921-1950 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (Spencer Lens). 1930-1950 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (Carl Zeiss). 1934-1937 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (various firms). (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Tree Ring Equipment: Correspondence (photography). 1929-1950 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Cycle Instruments: Photo-Periodograph (early work). 1913-1915 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Cycle Instruments: Automatic Periodograph (early construction). 1918-1920 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Cycle Instruments: Miniature Cycloscope. 1938-1942 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Cycle Instruments: Cycloscope (construction, equipment). 1921-1952 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Cycle Instruments: A.E.D. "Studies with the Cycloscope." 1938 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Cycle Instruments: A.E.D. various Cycloscope articles. 1913-1943 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Cycle Instruments: miscellaneous Cycloscope notes, papers, photographs. (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Cycle Instruments: Interpolator. 1951-1953 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Cycle Instruments: Movie Cyclograph (work by Vinton Brown). 1929-1930 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - "Solar Complex" Sticks, Tree Ring core samples (A.E.D.'s accompanying note: "Original method of finding solar complex in tree rings. See II pg. 124 of Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth for a result of this.). 1926 (Box 100)
  - Tree Ring Photo Sticks. (Box 101)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: notes from reading. 1900-1914 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: miscellaneous notes and computations. 1906-1912 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: work on Prescott and Flagstaff Areas. 1911-1912 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Century" Tables (Flagstaff). 1912 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: European summaries and curves. 1912-1913 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Windsor, Vt. measures. 1913 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Gross Rings. 1916 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Periodograph Analyses. 1918 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Early Photo Work. 1908-1919. (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Old Extensions." 1912-1913, 1918 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Miscellaneous work. 1918-1919 (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Cycle work (various). 1920-1925 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Cycle work (various). 1927 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Cycle work (various). 1928-1931 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Bear-Sabino village site. 1920-1921 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Analysis check. 1926-1928 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Cycle Synthesis" (including correspondence with D.C. Miller). 1916, 1927 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Swedish Skeleton Counts. 1930 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Hellman Relation," (includes "Possible SS Cycles in Trees"). 1930, 1933 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Cycle work (various). 1932-1934 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Cycle work (various). 1935 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Abbot Analysis Checks." May 1932 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Tree Growth and Rain Correlation." Autumn 1933 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Analysis checks--to be redistributed." 1932, 1934 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: cycle work by Dinsmore Alter (includes correspondence). 1932-1933 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: SS Numbers. 1922, 1929-1932, 1935 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Cycle References." 1930-1935 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Early H. Morris Collections. 1931-1935, 1937 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Metropolitan Water Curves. 1935 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Cycle work (various). 1936-1938 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Radio Reception: Daily Earth Currents," (includes correspondence with H.T. Stetson). 1938 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Brain Waves," (includes correspondence with Robert Cohn of St. Elizabeths Hospital, Washington, D.C.). 1937-1942 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Solar and Terrestial Work. 1943-1944 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: "Chilean Meteorology." Spring 1944 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Botany correlations and problems. (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Various Rainfall and Fog Recods. 1907-1953 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Tree Rings and Cycles: Reprints and articles by others. (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Cylce Notes. 1940-1954 (Box 106)
  - Cycle Notes. 1955-1960 (Box 107)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): correspondence with Carnegie Institution. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): plates. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): figures. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): miscellaneous material. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): first typing. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): final typing. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): "Thank-you" Letters. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume one): reviews. 1919 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): correspondence. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): outline, notes, discarded versions of parts. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): original draft, chapters I-IV. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): original draft, chapters V-VI. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): original draft, chapter VII. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): original draft, chapters VIII-IX. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): typed, chapters I-VI. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Climatic Cyles and Tree Growth (volume two): typed, chapters VII-IX. 1928 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): as sent to F.E. Clements, chapters I-IX. 1928 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): appendix and bibliography. 1928 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): galley proof (incomplete). 1928 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): preliminary drawings. 1928 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): original drawings as used. 1928 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): reviews. 1928 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume two): "By-Products and Left-Overs from Volume Two." 1928 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): original outline, plans, notes. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter I (introduction), drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter II, drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter III, drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 4)